Carolyn Weathers papers, 1971-2010 LSC.2223
UCLA Library Special Collections
Carolyn Weathers papers
1971-2010
LSC.2223
UCLA Library Special Collections
0.8 linear feet (2 boxes)
Carolyn Weathers is a lesbian activist and publisher. This collection contain flyers, brochures, publications, and other materials related to the operation of Clothespin Fever Press, a lesbian press founded by Carolyn Weathers and Jenny Wrenn in the 1980s.
Weathers, Carolyn
Conditions Governing Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Acquisition Information
Provenance unknown.
This collection is part of an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW), and the UCLA Library.
Sponsor
The June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive at UCLA is an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW), and the UCLA Library. These collections expand the pool of primary source materials available to researchers and to the community at large. This partnership was initiated by CSW and is funded by the National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) to inventory, organize, preserve, and digitize more than eighty Mazer collections pertaining to lesbian and feminist activism and writings.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 7594284
Biography
Born in 1941, Carolyn Weathers is the daughter of a Southern Baptist preacher. She moved to Los Angeles after being expelled from a Texas University when she came out as a lesbian. She was an enthusiastic participant in the pre-Stonewall bar scene in San Antonio, Texas and in the Gay Liberation Front and the Gay Women's Liberation Front at the Women's Center of Los Angeles.
She was a co-publisher with artist Jenny Wrenn, of Clothespin Fever Press, a now defunct lesbian book publishing company that operated from 1986-1994. Her stories and remembrances are included in Gay LA: A History of Sexual Outlaws, Power Politics and Lipstick Lesbians by Lillian Faderman and Stuart Timmons as well as in Feminists Who Changed America 1963-1975 edited by Barbara Love. She also wrote a memoir, titled Her Leaving Texas (1986). After retiring from her job as a public librarian for the Los Angeles Public Library, she began writing the column "True Life Lesbian Adventures" for the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives. Weathers was awarded with an LGBT Heritage Award by the City of Los Angeles In June 2015.
Scope and Content
This collection contain flyers, brochures, publications, and other materials related to the operation of Clothespin Fever Press, a lesbian press founded by Carolyn Weathers and Jenny Wrenn in the 1980s.
Organization and Arrangement
Materials arranged by type.
Related Material
Carolyn Weathers Photographs and Papers, Coll2014-008, ONE National Gay & Lesbian Archives, USC Libraries, University of Southern California.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
COLLECTION CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Clothespin Fever Press -- Archives.; June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive at UCLA.; June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives.; Weathers, Carolyn -- Archives; Feminist literature--Publishing.; Lesbian activists--California--Archives.
- The House of Pelham Falls by Brenda Weathers, undated (Box 1, Folders 1-2)
  Scope and Content
  Manuscript by Carolyn Weathers's sister Brenda, with editorial notes by Katherine Forrest.
- "A History of Clothespin Fever Press", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Narrative history of Clothespin Fever Press written by Carolyn Weathers in preparation for an event in their honor at ONE Institute and Archives in 2004.
- Flyers and brochures, 1976-1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Flyers for True Life Lesbian Adventures by Carolyn Weathers at the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives. Brochures for Women's Health and Healing Conference 1976 and the Westside Women's Clinic.
- Clothespin Fever Press catalogs, 1990-2004 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Lesbian Line, 1988-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Quarterly newspaper and catalogs for Clothespin Fever Press.
- Women's History postcards, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Clothespin Fever Press purchased these postcards from Helaine Victoria Press.
- Jenny Wrenn photo project, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Printed photo reproductions by Clothespin Fever Press co-founder Jenny Wrenn.
- Books, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Words in Our Pockets: How to Gain Power, Get Published and Get Paid: The Feminist Writers guild Handbook, ed. Celeste West (1985) and Womb with Views: A Contradictionary of the english language by Kate Musgrave (1989).
- Plaques, 1990-2010 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Invitation to the Inauguration Ceremony for the Mayor of Houston, Annise D. Parker and a plaque from Clothespin Fever Press to Ann Bradley for her "Excellent Work in Supporting And Promoting Lesbian Literature in Los Angeles."
- Audiovisual materials, 1971-2010 (Box 2)
  Includes recordings of Weathers' poetry readings, performances, interviews and other material related to Weather's career as a publisher and activist. Contains one VHS cassette, one audio disc, 9 DVDs with videorecordings, 1 DVD with slides, 3 audiocassettes, and one DVD titled "HomoFiles 6/30/2010 Marie Cartier + Carolyn Weathers" of unknown material.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. To review these audiovisual materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
  COLLECTION CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.